A Guide to the Rockingham Public Library Collection 1767-1873
Special Collections, Carrier Library, James Madison University
Special Collections, James Madison University
Rockingham Public Library Collection 1767-1873
Special Collections, James Madison University
3060
This collection consists of one Hollinger box.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
Received on deposit immediately after a Feb. 3, 1994 contract with the Rockingham Library Association was signed. Existing organization and file headings were retained.
Biographical/Historical Information
Contents relevant to Rockingham County and Harrisonburg from the earliest days of county formation, 1767-1873.
Scope and Content
This collection is comprised of mostly legal materials.
Arrangement
Series I: Court Cases; Series II: Roads, Bridges and Mills; Series III: Miscellaneous.
Contents List
- Court Cases
  - Specific Cases 1814-1831 (Box-folder 1:1)
    - Samuel Chandler Sr. vs. Nathan Chandler
    - Col. Arch Rutherford vs. Charles and David Chandler and Jacob Nicholas
  - General Court Cases (Box-folder 1:2)
    - Armentrout, Nicholas vs. Mathias Stover, Ohio 1818-1932
    - Beard, Margaret vs. David Beard 1824-1832
    - Harrison, Nath. & John Harrison vs. Archibald Looker 1832
    - Basely, Haga 1829
    - High, Jacob vs. Sally Knopp late Hupp admr. of John Hupp 1810
    - Huling vs. Looker 1820-1832
    - Looker, John vs. Henry Long 1829-1831
    - Lindon [?], Thomas, Wm. Robertson vs. Wm. Dever 1835-1838
    - Peters vs. Pence 1814-1839
    - Ragan, Daniel vs. M. Williams 1821-1830
    - Scott, James vs. Jacob Hudlow 1767-1822
  - McDowell, Miller vs. Wm. McMahon 1810-1831 (Box-folder 1:3)
  - Rifle, Daniel vs. John Smoot 1824-1832 (Box-folder 1:4)
- Roads Bridges, Mills
  - Bridge 1818 (Box-folder 1:5)
  - Briery Branch 1823-1825 (Box-folder 1:6)
  - Brocks Gap- Peaked Mtn.-Keezletown Dove's Mill Rd. 1824-1826 (Box-folder 1:7)
  - Dry River Road 1799-1834 (Box-folder 1:8)
  - Grist mill, Wise-Dinkle 1796-1851 (Box-folder 1:9)
  - Hands to work on roads 1823-1824 (Box-folder 1:10)
  - Harrisonburg to Richmond, McGaheysville to Luray, Pirkey's Mill 1822 (Box-folder 1:11)
  - Harrisonburg to Woodstock-Back Road 1824-1826 (Box-folder 1:12)
  - Keezletown to New Market 1826-1826 (Box-folder 1:13)
  - Lawyer Rd., Pt. Republick to Waynesboro 1822-1826 (Box-folder 1:14)
  - Mathias Stover Mill-Fawcett, Keezletown 1825 (Box-folder 1:15)
  - Mtn. Road, Chrisman's Mill 1822-1825 (Box-folder 1:16)
  - Road Related 1822-1826 (Box-folder 1:17)
  - Road to Shen. Cty. -Road past Henry Miller 1823 (Box-folder 1:18)
  - Stage Road-Zirkel & Byrd Mill 1805-1822 (Box-folder 1:19)
- Miscellaneous
  - African Americans 1778-1851 (Box-folder 1:20)
  - Debts 1787-1869 (Box-folder 1:21)
  - Estates and Complaints 1792-1858 (Box-folder 1:22)
  - Estray Livestock 1826-1851 (Box-folder 1:23)
  - Land causes 1796-1859 (Box-folder 1:24)
  - Miscellaneous 1779-1873 (Box-folder 1:25)
    mostly summonses; also list of bonds, election results, grand jury
  - Overseers of the Poor 1802-1809 (Box-folder 1:26)
  - Railroads 1855-1892 (Box-folder 1:27)
  - Rockingham Cty. seal receipt, Harrisonburg jail 1779-1855 (Box-folder 1:28)
  - Taxes 1783-1864 (Box-folder 1:29)
  - Tory: John Carthrae 1787 (Box-folder 1:30)